Not yet.
Draw them closer!
Fire!
Yoshitatsu.
War isn't simply a matter of
overwhelming the enemy.
Inaba has betrayed us!
What?
Ujiie and Andou have also defected!
The Mino Three have all betrayed us?
You've brought this on yourself, Father!
I won't allow you to turn Mino
Province over to that fool of a princess!
Kill Saitou Dousan!
Oda Nobuna no Yabou
The moment you swing the sword you pledged upon
You get hurt again
Biting down on my lip
I try to figure out what the right thing is
I will protect you, but before that
There's something I must do
I'm not trying to stand out
I just don't want to be a liar
I live on the battlefield with my life on the line
Whenever I look back, you're there to reassure me
The days of sorrow end, and the sun of ambition rises
Let's defeat fate and go as far as we want
Linking the world
Episode Three
The Mino
Disturbance
Episode Three
The Mino
Disturbance
Episode Three
The Mino
Disturbance
Episode Three
The Mino
Disturbance
Saitou Yoshitatsu rebelled?
All the nobles... of Mino
Province... are siding with him.
Unbelievable.
Saitou Yoshitatsu... is who they'd rather... have lead.
Stop pausing while you speak!
You know that ain't happening.
Dousan has left Inabayama Castle,
and is fighting an army that outnumbers his almost ten-to-one at the Nagara river.
The combat is fierce and...
Told you.
That's insanity.
Engaging them whilst in
the open and outnumbered...
Count Dousan intends to die there.
If he forces them to siege his castle,
our princess will send reinforcements.
That would mean that
Imagawa Yoshimoto
would be certain to attack
the now-empty Owari Province.
He wants to die before Nobuna acts?
Such resolve is worthy of
the title, "Viper of Mino."
Sixty points.
That's a low score for such a compliment.
When I think of how the princess feels...
Yeah.
I've heard what happened in Mino.
So, as for the reinforcements...
Don't send any.
Seriously?
If we went to save him,
he'd only lecture me.
You okay with that?
What's that look for?
Would you rather see me lose my head?
Well, no, but...
Then let me ask you.
If I said I would send
reinforcements, would you let me?
Okay! This conversation's over.
Wait!
I said it's over, so it's over!
Don't forget your place,
you stupid monkey!
It's just like with Nobukatsu.
I can understand why Imagawa
would want this place.
As do you, yes?
But the princess of the Oda is
the greatest fool in the land.
She may head to Mino on her own.
Then we're going with the Imagawa.
Yoshimoto's a woman, too.
She'll be easy for you to seduce.
I pity all the women who try to
rule during this Sengoku Era.
I'll take advantage of them all.
Sorry about earlier.
Don't come in without asking.
When it seemed like you didn't
care about the Viper, I just...
I know you really want to save him, too.
I'm sorry.
Will the Viper die?
The person who gave me this
was a barbarian missionary.
The person you care about?
As I was learning from them,
I decided I wanted to unite
Japan and travel the world.
That individual, who had come from across the sea,
was the beginning of my dream.
I'd like to meet that person, too.
He's already dead.
Sorry.
For some reason, all of the
people I love die quickly.
It was like that with Father, too.
And now, the Viper.
Maybe I can't love anybody.
That's not true.
Your face says, "I'm not going to die."
I'm pretty stubborn that way.
You'll be fine.
After all, I'll never love you.
What's that?
That's harsh.
I am the head of the Asai
clan, Asai Nagamasa.
I'm very honored to meet
such a beautiful princess.
Asai
Nagamasa
Asai Nagamasa is the young
count of northern Oumi.
Asai
Nagamasa
To reach the capital, one
must first get through him.
Asai
Nagamasa
Look at that asshole's smirk!
Come on, quiet down, Monkey!
You have a pet monkey?
Ignore him.
I'm still training him.
More importantly, what do you want?
I've come to remove the cause of
your suffering, Princess Nobuna.
My suffering?
Saitou Dousan of Mino.
As things are, he'll die within days.
But the Oda cannot act.
What of it?
If the Asai and Oda attack from
the north and south simultaneously,
the battle will end swiftly.
You'll be able to rescue Dousan.
And with Oumi, Mino, and Owari united,
even the Imagawa will not be able to stand against us.
You're proposing an alliance?
Doesn't it sound good?
Too good.
What are you really after?
Excuse me.
You're quite unlike the stories I've heard.
Well, then I'll be honest.
Oda Nobuna,
I've come to make you my wife.
We're losing badly.
What kind of monster
attacks his own father?
Father?
If he had even a portion of my blood,
he could have been friends
with young Nobuna.
Count Dousan, Inoue
has perished in battle.
Many have left us.
The enemy now number above 15,000.
None of them have the
slightest bit of loyalty!
Don't say that.
It may be impossible for any of them
to understand young Nobuna's genius.
Mitsuhide.
I have a request for you.
Y-Y-You want to get married?!
We'll be the most beautiful couple in Japan.
I-I-It's just way too sudden! That's crazy!
Right?
Beautiful couple?!
He's right! He's better looking than I am!
Let us conquer Japan together, Nobuna.
D-D-Does that mean you're in love with me?
No.
Political marriages are the way of the world.
If anything, love gets in the way.
What a jerk!
I want to...
choose my own husband.
I'm going to marry the person I love.
That's my dream!
Have you already decided on someone?
W-Well...
Oh, is it the monkey?
No!
This ape... is just my servant!
I'm never ever going to marry him!
What are you kicking me for?!
You say something, too!
But I'm just a servant.
You're giving up because he's
better looking than you?!
You're lame!
Who's giving up on what?
Well...
You're about to lose the
prettiest girl in the land!
Doesn't that bother you?
It does, right?
If you don't want to
do it, then just refuse.
I'll marry Nagamasa!
Go on, then!
I won't miss a girl who marries
someone who doesn't love her!
Shut up!
A lovers' quarrel in front of
another count is unacceptable.
Five points.
Lovers' quarrel?
That was certainly an unexpected ambush.
Well, um...
But if you refuse the marriage, Dousan will die.
You bastard! Are you blackmailing her?
Without Dousan in Mino and facing the Imagawa,
if you make an enemy of the Asai
as well, the Oda clan will fall.
You'd do well to think this over.
Nobuna...
There's still a way to save Count Dousan.
The knowledge of that
brought back all the emotions
she had sealed within her heat.
But she can't marry that man!
I feel bad for the princess.
The Imagawa armies gather at our borders.
We cannot go on our own.
And the alliance is the
strategically correct choice.
You're not going to accept
this marriage are you?
If the Oda Clan's only interest
is in conquering Japan,
this marriage is...
seventy points.
However!
If we think of our princess,
then it's less than zero points.
Women are not tools of conquest!
Nagahide...
With all of the wars going on,
I'd at least hoped our princess...
Monkey?
...ended up with someone she liked.
Hey, lowlife!
If you want to seduce a girl,
there are better ways to go about it!
She may not look it,
but Nobuna's very naïve!
A loveless marriage proposal is
too much of a shock for her!
A man's jealousy is an ugly thing.
Th-That's not it!
I won't say that a political
marriage is a bad thing,
but you should at least
tell her you like her!
Telling a lie like that is worse.
If you want to be a countess,
you have to throw away any
chance of happiness as a woman.
You can't stay a woman if you
want to survive the Sengoku Era.
If she hopes for both love
and the unification of Japan,
it's better that someone make her give up that naïve dream early.
That's the kind thing to do.
Shut up!
I swore I'd make her dream come true!
If she won't give up
on conquest or love,
I'll make sure she gets both of them!
So... So, if you could at least...
I don't love her.
And I never will.
Why you...
I'm going to keep having
her carve up provinces.
For me, her husband.
You monster!
No, Monkey!
Let me go, Inuchiyo.
If you hit him, there'll be war.
You're just one of her retainers.
No matter how much you
love her, it will never be.
Never.
Damn it!
Never, huh?
Have you made your decision, Nobuna?
I-I...
This will solve all your problems.
I... I will m... ma—
Stop right there!
I won't give Nobuna to you!
Never.
Monkey...
I mean the Oda aren't going
to be the Asai's slaves.
Don't get the wrong idea.
I won't!
Get out of here, Monkey.
This is a matter between count—
I won't give our princess
to a womanizer like you!
You both lose points for not being
honest with yourselves, but...
eighty points.
Discussions are over.
I hope you don't regret it.
I'm glad that's over.
Akechi Mitsuhide has come from Mino.
You guys...
Where's the Viper?
The Viper's with you, right?
Count Dousan's daughter, Mistress Kichou.
What happened to the Viper?
I have a letter.
Oda Nobuna, my daughter.
When I met you, I learned
that my dream was not over.
I learned that the life I spent
expanding my borders was not in vain.
I could have no greater joy.
All men will die someday.
The time to say goodbye
will come to us all.
If Oda Nobuna will carry on the dream of the Viper, that is enough for me.
I leave now for the next world,
praying that your dreams come true.
C-Count Dousan repeats:
he does not need reinforcements...
All forces...
All forces, march—
I'm sorry!
...for Mino.
K-Katsuie!
We can't send reinforcements!
When she wakes, do you intend
on telling her Dousan died?
What else can we do?!
Send out a strike force
to rescue Dousan.
But they'll never survive!
Who would we send?
I'll go!
Thanks, Goemon.
A servant should do
anything for their lord.
Boss, we going to war?
We steal the Viper of Mino.
Sounds like a big job.
Anyone who makes it through the enemy lines alive, head to my daughter in Owari!
I'll show you how a viper dies!
Wait!
Boy, what are you doing here?
You're coming with us, old man.
I refuse!
You stubborn old man!
Do you know how sad
Nobuna will be if you die?
You stupid fool!
What?
What if you die here?
You are her one hope.
I-I am?
A dream is a dream because
you share it with someone.
You are from the future, and the only
one who can understand her dream.
A dream only one person
has is nothing but ambition.
Will this land be burned by
ambition or brightened by dreams?
Its fate rests on your shoulders.
Lead Nobuna for me.
I understand.
But I'm taking you back with me.
Y-You moron!
She's not honest with
herself, and she's a brat,
but she accidentally told me how she felt!
For some reason, all of the
people I love die quickly.
I never want to see her that sad again!
Where am I?
What happened in Mino?
Where's Monkey?
Um, well... Basically...
Where did he go?!
Mino.
Hurry, Goemon!
I'm giving it my all!
We're sitting ducks out here!
We'll have to trust our luck to heaven.
Fire! Keep on firing!
Don't let my father escape!
Props, Goemon!
Props?
It means "Thank you."
H-Hang in there!
Count Dousan, I hope your dream comes true.
Goodbye.
I'm sorry.
Sagara, any plans?
Didn't that "game" of yours
tell you anything about this?
This wasn't part of the game!
We'll have to make it on our own!
My father will soon
be arriving in Owari.
Don't let him escape.
Kill him!
Yes, sir!
We're through!
We made it to Owari, old man!
Not yet, boy.
Yoshitatsu will not give up so easily.
We need to run!
We can't. The horses are faster!
So, this is it?
Push the Yoshitatsu army back!
Charge!
Retreat! Retreat!
What's Nobuna doing here?
And why has she brought
half the Owari army?
If we leave Owari defenseless,
Imagawa will attack!
Nobody stopped her?
We tried. But she insisted...
But...
It's your fault!
You just went and left me.
You can't even use a spear!
What if you had died?!
Nobuna...
Reporting.
25,000 Imagawa troops have invaded Owari.
tada jidai no mannaka tatasarete tomadou toki ni
When I, lost in time, was standing there confused
te wo hiite kureta hito e dekiru koto sagashita
You pulled me through, so I wanted to do something in return
kizutsuki nagara warau sugata
You were smiling even though you were being hurt
kokoro no ura namida ga mieta
I saw you shedding tears deep inside
sukui motomeru koe kikitoreru no wa
I could only understand your call for help
yurusareta mono dake
When you opened up to me
kazoe kirenu arashi wo koete
I will overcome the countless storms
anata no yami saku hikari ni naru
And become the light that cuts through your darkness
mou mayowanai tomo ni ikitai
I won't hesitate anymore; let's go together
chikau yume ga donna mubou de atte mo
No matter how unrealistic our ambitions are
oboeteite shinjirareru basho wa
Remember there's a place you can believe in
koko ni aru to
Right here
Episode Four
Winds of Change!
Okehazama!
Episode Four
Winds of Change!
Okehazama!
Episode Four
Winds of Change!
Okehazama!
Episode Four
Winds of Change!
Okehazama!